

NGAN LE

Manual QC

Email: nganle.180200@gmail.com

Phone: +84 394793303 Address: Binh Thanh dist, HCMC

Github: github.com/hellen-yeuoi/Personal **Linkedin:** linkedin.com/in/ngan-le-a85063214

ABOUT

I have 2 years of experience working as Manual Tester for Production Companies applying and using Agile & Scrum. And have Basic knowledge of SQL, Database and Requirement Engineering, fundamental ISTQB,..; familiar with Postman, Jira.

For short term (3 years), I would like to more have experience in software development and testing life cycle. (SDLC & STLC).

In a long term direction, I aim to be at the senior level of QC, master testing skills on both manual and automation.

EXPERTISE

Detail Oriented

Analyze UX/UI

Requirements Analyze User Story

User Story description and clarification

Requirement Specification and Clarification

Requirement Management Validation

Exploratory Test

Manual Test

Adhoc Test

Smoke Test

Design Test

Test case execution

Test Report

API Test with postman

EDUCATION

Bachelor Degree Van Lang University

2018-2022

Major: Business Administration

Specialization: Information Systems Management (ISM)

GPA: 3.07/4.0

LANGUAGE

Vietnamese ==



English



CERTIFICATES



Dec 2020 Vietnam Digital 4.0 - Google Certification

Nov 2020 SOL - Solo Learn Certification

Oct 2021 Agile & Scrum training - DEK Technologies Certification

Dec 2022 ISTOB - Course Certificate Testing Viet Nam

WORKING HISTORY

FABOSHOP LIMITED LIABILITY COMPANY - June 2022 - Present

Description: E-Commerce Product (Product)

Role: Quality Control - (Middle)

Activities:

- Participate in testing 2 products CDN & BO(internal)
- Working in an Agile environment
- Manual UI and functional test on browser extension, mobile app and web app.
- Writing postman pre-request and post-request scripts to validate input/output of apis.
- Raising bug's tickets on Jira to log bugs
- Writing checklist
- Writing release report by sprint

MINESKI GLOBAL - Dec 2022 - Jul 2023 (shift-time)

Description: Gaming Service (Outsource)

Role: Quality Control - (Junior-Middle)

Activities:

- Participate in testing M-tournament Flatform
- Working in an Agile environment
- Raising bug's tickets on Jira to log bugs
- Test Web app
- Test design
- Manual test API

EGOHITEK JOINT STOCK COMPANY - Dec 2021 - Jun 2022

Description: HR Management Applications (Product)

Role: Quality Control Intern (Intern, Fresher)

Activities:

- Working in an Agile environment
- Analyzing product requirements
- Analyzing Activity diagram
- Writing testcases
- Raising bug's tickets on Jira to log bugs
- Learning teamwork, analytical, problem solving skills

GB. SOFT CO.,LTD - Oct 2021 - Feb 2022

Description: Outsource

Role: Business Analyst (Intern)

Activities:

- Analyzing customer's requests (Sakuko, IGC)
- Creating testcase and testing customer's website (Sakuko, IGC, USA Mua, Huong Bao)
- Writing content for E-commerce website & for some customer's website

(Sakuko, TC Hyundai, Grove fresh, Sakos)